Joyeeta Mukherjee

(510) 309-6249 tsrumia@gmail.com Farmington NY, 14425

Software developer, with expertise in Java, Angular, C#, SQL, C++, JavaScript and HTML. Provided technical leadership in projects with experience on the manufacturing floor. Researched deep space networks with NASA as part of thesis work. Strong desire to learn, exploiting technical skills with dedication and innovation.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Language proficiencies in Java, C#, SQL, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Developed projects in Angular and Magento
- Sound understanding of software engineering concepts and OOP principles
- Experienced with Agile Software Development Methodologies
- Used GIT, SVN, TFS for tracking project updates
- Able to meet deadlines, attaining perfection in all work
- Quick learner, team player with great communication and presentation skills

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Individually designed and developed Multihopper testing app and successfully delivered it to the manufacturing floor contributing to the company's net profit. Received individual company wide recognition for the same
- 2. Developed estore for automating manual company sales efforts. Extraordinary contribution and recognition for the same
- Worked in collaboration with NASA, JPL to design the IPN for testing on terrestrial testbed. Master's thesis work on the same and recognized by NASA for successful project completion
- 4. Worked together with my team at Entrust Datacard for development of an in house data analysis application, tailored to meet company wide data analysis and visualization needs
- 5. Designed and implemented Wireless Sensor Network that checks the temperature and rate of water flowing through cooling pipes and performing analysis.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Entrust Datacard, Shakopee August 2016

- August 2016 November 2017
- Automation Software Developer, to automate manual processes throughout the company using agile methodologies.
- At the same time working in three different projects with different technologies.

- Extensive work in C#, Magento and Angular. Worked using SSMS, Oracle. Was also involved with extensive UI development.
- Used Jira, git and TFS to track projects.

OATI, Greater Minneapolis

November 2012 - May 2013

- Software Developer, to design and develop web based application using agile software development methodologies.
- Extensive work in Java and with databases using MS SQL Server 2008/2012. This involved working with stored procedures, tables, sql queries and SQL server jobs.
- Used TFS for tracking work items and testing.

HCL Technologies, India

August 2007 - April 2009

- Software Engineer, specifically working as testing engineer for web application LNRE
- Manual testing and Automation testing experience with QTP. Also acquainted with Ruby and SilkTest scripts
- Developing Test Plans and Test Cases
- Quality maintenance and configuration control for an entire project and team and generating reports for the Client. Also perform Project risk and Cost analysis

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Master in Computer Science (2011-2012)

University of Nebraska-Lincoln (GPA – 3.7)

 Thesis on implementing an Interplanetary Internet (IPN) on terrestrial test beds for Outer Space Networks – "Routing over the IPN".

Master of Computer Application (2004-2007)

University of Calcutta, Kolkata, India (GPA – 3.8)

Bachelors in Science (with Honors in Computer Science) (2001-2004)

Syamaprasad College, University of Calcutta, Kolkata, India (GPA – 4.0)

PUBLICATIONS

- Mukherjee and B. Ramamurthy, "<u>Communication Technologies and Architectures for Space Network and Interplanetary Internet</u>", IEEE 15 Communications Surveys & Tutorials, no. 2 (2013): 881-897(Impact factor-6.311)
- Mukherjee and B. Ramamurthy, "<u>The Interplanetary Internet Implemented on a Terrestrial testbed</u>", Ad Hoc Networks (2015), Elsevier. An earlier version was presented at the Communications (ICC), 2013 IEEE International Conference on. IEEE, 2013.

WEBSITE https://mukherj.github.io/website/home